{
  "isTheory": true,
  "openingRemarks": "Find the solution to the following equations",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{3}{4}a - \\dfrac{1}{3} = \\dfrac{1}{2}a + \\dfrac{5}{6} \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{3}{4}a - \\dfrac{1}{3} &= \\dfrac{1}{2}a + \\dfrac{5}{6} \\\\\n12 \\times \\dfrac{3}{4}a - 12 \\times \\dfrac{1}{3} &= 12 \\times \\dfrac{1}{2}a + 12 \\times \\dfrac{5}{6} \\\\\n3 \\times 3a - 4 \\times 1 &= 6 \\times a + 2 \\times 5 \\\\\n9a - 4 &= 6a + 10 \\\\\n9a - 6a &= 10 + 4 \\\\\n3a &= 14 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3a}{3} &= \\dfrac{14}{3} \\\\\na &= \\dfrac{14}{3}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{3}{4}a - \\dfrac{1}{3}\\) if \\(a=\\dfrac{14}{3}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{3}{4}a - \\dfrac{1}{3} &= \\dfrac{3}{4}\\left(\\dfrac{14}{3}\\right) - \\dfrac{1}{3} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{7}{2} - \\dfrac{1}{3} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{19}{6}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{1}{2}a + \\dfrac{5}{6}\\) if \\(a=\\dfrac{14}{3}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{2}a + \\dfrac{5}{6} &= \\dfrac{1}{2}\\left(\\dfrac{14}{3}\\right) + \\dfrac{5}{6} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{7}{3} + \\dfrac{5}{6} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{19}{6}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{1}{2}(k+3) = \\dfrac{1}{3}(k + 16) \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{2}(k+3) &= \\dfrac{1}{3}(k + 16) \\\\\n6 \\times \\dfrac{1}{2}(k + 3) &= 6 \\times \\dfrac{1}{3}(k + 16) \\\\\n3(k + 3) &= 2(k + 16) \\\\\n3k + 9 &= 2k + 32 \\\\\n3k - 2k &= 32 - 9 \\\\\nk &= 23\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{1}{2}(k+3)\\) if \\(k=23\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{2}(k+3) &= \\dfrac{1}{2}(23+3) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{1}{2}(26) \\\\\n&= 13\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{1}{3}(k+16)\\) if \\(k=23\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{3}(k+16) &= \\dfrac{1}{3}(23+16) \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{1}{3}(39) \\\\\n&= 13\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(0.8x - 0.3 = 0.7x + 0.2 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.8x - 0.3 &= 0.7x + 0.2 \\\\\n0.8x - 0.7x &= 0.2 + 0.3 \\\\\n0.1x &= 0.5 \\\\\n\\dfrac{0.1x}{0.1} &= \\dfrac{0.5}{0.1} \\\\\nx &= 5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.8x - 0.3\\) if \\(x=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.8x - 0.3 &= 0.8(5) - 0.3 \\\\\n&= 4 - 0.3 \\\\\n&= 3.7\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.7x + 0.2\\) if \\(x=5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.7x + 0.2 &= 0.7(5) + 0.2 \\\\\n&= 3.5 + 0.2 \\\\\n&= 3.7\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(0.36a + 2.55 = 0.41a + 6.8 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.36a + 2.55 &= 0.41a + 6.8 \\\\\n0.36a - 0.41a &= 6.8 - 2.55 \\\\\n-0.05a &= 4.25 \\\\\n\\dfrac{-0.05a}{-0.05} &= \\dfrac{4.25}{-0.05} \\\\\na &= -85\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.36a + 2.55\\) if \\(a=-85\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.36a + 2.55 &= 0.36(-85) + 2.55 \\\\\n&= -30.6 + 2.55 \\\\\n&= -28.05\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.41a + 6.8\\) if \\(a=-85\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.41a + 6.8 &= 0.41(-85) + 6.8 \\\\\n&= -34.85 + 6.8 \\\\\n&= -28.05\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(0.6p - 1.9 = 0.78p + 1.7 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.6p - 1.9 &= 0.78p + 1.7 \\\\\n0.6p - 0.78p &= 1.7 + 1.9 \\\\\n-0.18p &= 3.6 \\\\\n\\dfrac{-0.18p}{-0.18} &= \\dfrac{3.6}{-0.18} \\\\\np &= -20\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = RHS</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.6p - 1.9\\) if \\(p=-20\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.6p - 1.9 &= 0.6(-20) - 1.9 \\\\\n&= -12 - 1.9 \\\\\n&= -13.9\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.78p + 1.7\\) if \\(p=-20\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.78p + 1.7 &= 0.78(-20) + 1.7 \\\\\n&= -15.6 + 1.7 \\\\\n&= -13.9\n\\end{align*}\n\\]"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(0.10d + 0.05(d - 4) = 2.05 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.10d + 0.05(d - 4) &= 2.05 \\\\\n0.10d + 0.05d - 0.2 &= 2.05 \\\\\n0.15d &= 2.05 + 0.2 \\\\\n0.15d &= 2.25 \\\\\n\\dfrac{0.15d}{0.15} &= \\dfrac{2.25}{0.15} \\\\\nd &= 15\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 2.05</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.10d + 0.05(d - 4)\\) if \\(d=15\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.10d + 0.05(d - 4) &= 0.10(15) + 0.05(15 - 4) \\\\\n&= 1.5 + 0.05(11) \\\\\n&= 1.5 + 0.55 \\\\\n&= 2.05 \n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(n - 18 = 31 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nn - 18 &= 31 \\\\\nn &= 31 + 18 \\\\\nn &= 49\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 31</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(n - 18\\) if \\(n=49\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\nn - 18 &= 49 - 18 \\\\\n&= 31\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(9c = 144 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n9c &= 144 \\\\\n\\dfrac{9c}{9} &= \\dfrac{144}{9} \\\\\nc &= 16\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 144</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(9c\\) if \\(c=16\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n9c &= 9(16) \\\\\n&= 144\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(4y - 8 = 16 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4y - 8 &= 16 \\\\\n4y &= 16 + 8 \\\\\n4y &= 24 \\\\\n\\dfrac{4y}{4} &= \\dfrac{24}{4} \\\\\ny &= 6\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 16</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(4y - 8\\) if \\(y=6\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n4y - 8 &= 4(6) - 8 \\\\\n&= 24 - 8 \\\\\n&= 16\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(-8x - 15 + 9x - 1 = -21 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-8x - 15 + 9x - 1 &= -21 \\\\\n-8x + 9x &= -21 + 15 + 1 \\\\\nx &= -5\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = -21</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(-8x - 15 + 9x - 1\\) if \\(x=-5\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n-8x - 15 + 9x - 1 &= -8(-5) - 15 + 9(-5) - 1 \\\\\n&= 40 - 15- 45 - 1 \\\\\n&= -21\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(\\dfrac{1}{4}p + \\dfrac{1}{3} = \\dfrac{1}{2} \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{4}p + \\dfrac{1}{3} &= \\dfrac{1}{2} \\\\\n12 \\times \\dfrac{1}{4}p + 12 \\times \\dfrac{1}{3} &= 12 \\times \\dfrac{1}{2} \\\\\n3p + 4 &= 6 \\\\\n3p &= 6 - 4 \\\\\n3p &= 2 \\\\\n\\dfrac{3p}{3} &= \\dfrac{2}{3} \\\\\np &= \\dfrac{2}{3}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = \\(\\dfrac{1}{2}\\)</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(\\dfrac{1}{4}p + \\dfrac{1}{3}\\) if \\(p=\\dfrac{2}{3}\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n\\dfrac{1}{4}p + \\dfrac{1}{3} &= \\dfrac{1}{4}\\left(\\dfrac{2}{3}\\right) + \\dfrac{1}{3} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{1}{6} + \\dfrac{1}{3} \\\\\n&= \\dfrac{1}{2}\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    },
    {
      "question": "\\(0.1d + 0.25(d + 8) = 4.1 \\)",
      "answer": "\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.1d + 0.25(d + 8) &= 4.1 \\\\\n0.1d + 0.25d + 2 &= 4.1 \\\\\n0.1d + 0.25d &= 4.1 - 2 \\\\\n0.35d &= 2.1 \\\\\n\\dfrac{0.35d}{0.35} &= \\dfrac{2.1}{0.35} \\\\\nd &= 6\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n\n<div>Check LHS = 4.1</div>\n\n<div>Evaluate \\(0.1d + 0.25(d + 8)\\) if \\(d=6\\)</div>\n\n\\[\n\\begin{align*}\n0.1d + 0.25(d + 8) &= 0.1(6) + 0.25(6 + 8) \\\\\n&= 0.6 + 0.25(14) \\\\\n&= 0.6 + 3.5 \\\\\n&= 4.1\n\\end{align*}\n\\]\n"
    }
  ]
}
